Tompkins Cortland Labor Coalition Records 6185
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- work related subjects, 1984-1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Chemicals Magazine articles, research paper (draft) on workplace evaluation for occupational disease, pamphlets, memos, handwritten notes on various health and work related subjects. Booklet on toxic hazards.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Getting information, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Management Copy of "Health & Safety Fact Sheet" (newsletter from AFL-CIO), example of US Dept. of Labor's "Log and Summary of Occupational Injuries and Illnesses", copy of OSHA 200 Log Case Study", magazine articles, memos, pamphlets, booklets, copy of "Worker's Guide to Recordkeeping Requirements Under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970"
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Inspectors, 1984-2000 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Inspectors/Testing/Surveys. UAW Industrial Hygiene Surveys, Indoor Air Quality Employee Questionnaire, Hazard information sheets and questionnaires, VDT Workstation Checklist, magazine articles, different work related surveys used to determine health hazards, OSHA inspection form and information, newspaper clipping.Books - "Job Hazard Analysis" by US Dept. of Labor, and "Talking Union 1-On-1".
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Accidents, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Investigating accidents. Articles, memos, forms, booklet "A Union Representatives Guide to Accident Investigation" by Jim Howe, Assistant Director, UAW Health and Safety Dept.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Labor Management Commission, 1986-1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Labor Management Commission. E-mails, correspondence, memos, handwritten notes, magazine articles on occupational safety and health.Books - "Occupational Safety and Health: Worksite Safety and Health Programs Show Promise" and "Occupational Safety & Health Programs Show Promise" by US General Accounting Office. "The Role of Labor-Management Committees in Safeguarding Worker Safety and Health" by US Dept. of Labor."Check-list and Guidelines for Joint Occupational Health and Safety Committees" by Canadian Centre for Occupational Health and Safety. "Guide to Effective Joint Labor/Management Safety & Health Committees" by Public Employees Occupational Safety and Health Program.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Medical Surveillance, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Magazine article about medical screenings and medical surveillance -- checklist
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Meetings, 1991-1995 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  Correspondence regarding upcoming conferences and meegtings.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Refusing Unsafe Work, 1973-1991 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  Magazine articles, memos, fact sheets, training memos, "Arbitral Value Judgments in Health and Safety Disputes" by James Gross from the Buffalo Law Review, v.54, zerox copies of cases from the Supreme Court Reporter.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Sample letters (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Sample request letters for: worker to obtain his/her exposure records, request for employers written plan, worker to obtain his/her medical records, release employee medical records to a union representative, employee or the union to obtain information on chemical exposures, employee to obtain the OSHA 200 Log of Inquiries and Illnesses.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Schools, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  Several papers on work environment at the University of Lowell of Lowell, Mass., newspaper clippings.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Training, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  Newspaper clippings, training memos on health & safety, union memos, handwritten notes on training outlines, book "Health and Safety for Inside Strategies".
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Training Case Study Sheets, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  Case Study SheetsCopies of Stewards Health and Safety training - cases, a "Factsheet" from London Hazards Centre, survey sheets, handwritten notes on how to conduct training and surveys.
- Health & Safety -- Committees -- Training Course Brochures, 1991-1997 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  Training Course Brochures Flyers, pamphlets, information sheets for training in occupational safety.
- Health & Safety -- Committees - Workers Comp. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  United Steelworkers of America - compensation booklet.
- Health & Safety -- Committees - Writing for the Reader, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  Workshop paperwork, memos that give tips and guidelines to improve writing skills for individuals who design written materials for their organizations.
- Health & Safety -- Correspondence, 1989-1994 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  Correspondence and letters to the editor related to health & safety issues.
- Health & Safety -- NYS Nursing Home Workers, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  Susan Harwood Training Grant Program, Ergo-Awareness, Program Review/Needs Assessment, Basics of Health & Safety, Control of hazardous Energy, Chemical Safety in Laboratories, Avoiding Obstacles.
- Health & Safety -- NYS Nursing Home Workers, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  Workshop Eval. Evaluations for the following workshops: Health & Safety Committees, Ergonomics/Hazards, Getting Information on Hazards, OSHA Rights, Family Medical Leave Act (FMLA)
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Back belts, 1991-2001 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  Corespondence, magazine articles, booklet "Workplace Use of Back Belts" by US Dept. of Health and Human Services, newspaper clippings, memos.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Back Injuries, 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  Surveys and survey results showing the number of back injuries and causes for custodians at Cornell.Correspondence, and educational articles on preventing back injuries.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Boyce Thomsen Ventilation, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  Correspondence about poor ventilation and concerns about mold at Boyce Thomsen.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Cashiers, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  Correspondence and notes about concerns of working conditions for cashiers on campus.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Confined Space, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Correspondence about concerns of employees who have to deal with confined spaces. Correspondence about setting up training sessions, training material, session roster list, reports on possible safety violations. Copy of "Cornell University Confined Space Entry Program and Permit Entry Procedures"
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Contract language (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Memo stating access to information on health & safety issues.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Dining, 1993-2000 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Ergonomics recommedations, correspondence discussing problems and solutions for job related injuries, surveys, statistics with recommendations for best and worst places to work. Written results of a Health & Safety walk thru of facilities with concerns and recommendations, employee survey, phone list for employees surveyed."Application of Occupational Ergonomics to Univ. Cafeteria Food Preparation and Service" submitted to Faculty/Staff Health program by Cornell.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Engineering Library, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Correspondence about the indoor air quality concerns at the Engineering Library.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Ergonomics Committee, 1994-1996 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Handwritten notes, committee meeting minutes, correspondence, copy of ergonomics recommendations for dining (Punnett Report).Risk factor exercise report for food service workers, and Ergonomics Committee: Punnett Report - meeting minutes.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Gannett Health Center, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Correspondence about OSHA violations made at Gannett Health Center.Also correspondence on the resolution.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Garage (CU Transit), 1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Correspondence about OSHA violations and copy of "Notice of Contest and Request for Informal Conference"
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - General information, 1986-1996 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Copy of Cornell University's Health and Safety document (Policy #2.4), copy of a Cornell University "Facts 1990-91" booklet. Copy of Personnel Manual - Resolving Employee Concerns". Correspondence, memos, and newspaper clippings. book by UAW Local 2300 - "Cornell Wages and Poverty: A Comparative Study of Service and Maintenance Employees' Wages"
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - General Stores, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Correspondence sighting violations found during a walk thru.Correpsondence regarding employee concerns of violations, roster for training. Back clinic evaluation sheets.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Grounds, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Handwritten notes and correspondence about confined space training for the Grounds Dept.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Injuries, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  E-mails and memos concerning injuries of custodians and food service workers. Notes give numbers, location and type of injury. Correspondence and written documentation of injuries at Cornell Univ., lists of contact names and numbers at Cornell.Copy of "Musculoskeletal Injury Prevention Program" by Cornell Univ. Information on training, warning signs and walk thru assessments of Cornell Dining.Copy of "Repetitive Strain Injury: A Handbook fo Dining Workers at Cornell University" by UAW2300.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Injury & Illness - UA, 1996-2001 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Correspondence requesting statistics of injuries at Cornell. Stats of injuries and illnesses, days of work lost
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Plant Science, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Correpondence and report follow-up to a complaint about air-quality. Handwritten notes about conversations held regarding these issues.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Policy, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  Copy of Cornell University's Health & Safety Policy.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Press, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  Correspondence from US Dept. of Labor citing violations of OSHA that were found during site inspection.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Print Shop, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  Correspondence and notes with recommendations for correcting problems found when inspecting the Print Shop (ventilation, humidity, etc). Correspondence about ventilation and other problems at Martha Van Print Shop.Questionnaire given to Martha Van employees about ventilation. Handwritten notes on problems and contact numbers.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Punnett Report, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  "Summary of Ergonomic Recommendations for Dining", conclusions of Punnett Report, and ergonomic assessment of selected jobs at Cornell Univ. Dining Facilities. Copy of report.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Repetitive Stress Injury Clinic, 1995-1998 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  Flyers, correspondence and surveys about RSI screening. Repetitive Stress information packet handed out at the free screening done on campus.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Handbook, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  Photos, correspondence, cartoons, copy of handbook.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Residents Life, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  Correspondence discussing the use and the dangers of chemicals by Residents Life employees.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - RPU (Robert Purcell Union), 1990 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  Correspondence and notes about a safety walk thru on Oct. 30, 1990.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Surveys, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  Survey results from employees on campus with health and safety concerns/problems.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Training Material, 1999-2001 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  Traning materials used in seminars, correspondence, handwritten notes from investigations, articles of interest. Inspection checklist, evaluation of training.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Uris Hall IAQ (Indoor Air Quality), 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  Correspondence concerning the indoor air quality in Uris Hall. Questionnaires received from Uris employees explaining symptoms and complaints.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Vet School, 1990-1994 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  Staff survey about worker concerns, correspondence and memos discussing environmental issues.Correspondence explaining concerns, investigation of concerns and possible remedies. Newspaper clippings. "Veterinary Research Tower Indoor Air Quality Summary Report"Correspondence about inspection of the barn area of the Vet School and violations that were found.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Warren Hall (Print Shop), 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  Health & Safety - - Cornell - Warren Hall (Print Shop) "Health Hazard Evaluation Report" by NIOSH Investigator - Edward A. Kaiser for Cornell Univ.Correspondence about air quality concerns, sight inspections and possible remedies for the Warren Hall Print Shop.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Water contamination, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  (8/1989). Reports and correspondence about "Drewgard 187", accidently getting into the potable water in the Ag Quad and how the situation was handled.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - West Campus Dumpsters (Box 12, Folder 28)
  Health & Safety -- Cornell - West Campus Dumpsters Handwritten notes from interviews with employees with complaints about using the dumpsters on West Campus.
- Health & Safety -- Cornell - Willard Straight Dining, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  Survey, correspondence concerning noise levels for employees working mainly in a pantry area of Williard Straight Dining.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases -- AFCU (Alternatives Federal Credit Union), 1991 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  Correspondence about copier fumes.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - AFGW Local 1013 (American Flint Glass Workers Union), 1996-1998 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  Discomfort and injury survey results, ergonomic report. Newspaper clippings.Philips Lighting brochure.Correspondence, statistics & surveys dealing with health and safety hazards at Philips and how they should be corrected.Training and general information material.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases -- Bath Village Workers, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 32)
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Beverly J. Martin -- Information, 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Information Newspaper clippings, handwritten notes from interviews about Indoor Air Quality. Copy of staff directory at Beverly J. Martin.Correspondence both internal and external discussing concerns of Indoor Air Quality.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Beverly J. Martin -- Renovation, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Renovation Map of school, handwritten notes of problems and concerns, room by room.Memo on walk-thru in May 1998.Memos from Site Based Committee on repairs need at BJM.Corresopondence about concerns within BJM.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases -- Biggs Bldg (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, notes, news articles, letters to editor, info on Biggs Bldg.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Boynton/Dewitt, 1989-1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Correspondence about indoor air quality problems. Health Questionnaire summary and air sample summary from 1993.Indoor Air Quality Investigation, Executive Summary for Dewitt Middle School & Belle Sherman Annex.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Brewer Tichener/UAW 1774 (Cooper), 1986-1992 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Correspondence discussing health & safety issues in the Brewer Tichener (Cooper) plant in Cortland. Training information, and articles showing ways to correct or improve working conditions.Workplace surveys about health & safety issues.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Buckbee-Mears Company (BMC), 2003 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Handwritten notes and training roster for training on understanding OSH resources.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Corning Hospital/Founders Pavilion, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Correspondence with Union Local 200A requesting a walk-thru of Corning Hospital and setting up arrangements.Related articles and information sheets.Correspondence and statistics about Corning Hospital's health & safety record.Training opportunities for the staff.Copies of minutes from the hospitals Safety Committee meetings.Copies of the Collective Bargaining Agreement between the Union and the RNs, LPNs, Service and Maintenance Workers for 1996/97 and 2000/2001.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Corning Teachers Assoc. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Handwritten notes of health & safety concerns expressed by Teachers Assoc. President.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Cortland Area Schools, 1998-2002 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  OSHA information sheets for both teachers and students listing worker rights. List of general sources of information and assistance with workplace issues.Training material notes, newspaper articles.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases -- Cortland Corset (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Referral form and notes
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Cortland County, 1991-1994 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  CSEA 812 list of DOT workers, workplace survey given to Cortland area workers to check on workplace hazards.Copy of paperwork discussing workplace investigations of hazards.Related magazine articles, correspondence about various violations or concerns.Newspaper clippings, investigation narratives.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Cortland County Personnel, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  Correspondence trying to set up training sessions for Cortland County employees.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Cortland Works Career Center, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  Career Center Paperwork and course material from NYS Dept. of Labor for training on workplace health & safety.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - CSEA 561, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  Material Safety Data Sheet (MSDS) with hazard information about Corcraft Floor Wax Remover (floor stripper).Correspondence reporting possible health hazards.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - CSEA 605 (SUNY Cortland), 1989-1995 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  Represents office, custodial, maintenance, grounds, boiler plant and general stores employees.Paperwork about health and safety training.Correspondence on specific concerns on campus.Questionnaires on hand/wrist cumulative trauma. Map of campus.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - CSEA 849 (Schuyler County Highway Dept.), 1993 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  Correspondence about work related injuries and concerns. Correspondence on follow up to training session on how to help or prevent the hazards in question (back, VDT use, etc.)
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - CSEA 855 (Tompkins County Dept. of Public Works) (Box 13, Folder 17)
  Copy of Safety Council By-Laws.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Dewitt Middle School, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  Indoor Air Quality survey given to Dewit Middle School employees. Correspondence about the survey.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Econolodge, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  Paperwork sighting alleged safety or health hazards at the Econolodge on Triphammer Rd., Ithaca.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Emerson Power Transmission/Borg Warner, 1990-1994 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  Injury and illnesses tally sheets. Executive Board Address list.Correspondence on health & safety training, survey, and questionnaire.Correspondence about IAM 1607 withdrawing from TCLC.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Fingerlakes Library, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  Handwritten notes and correspondence concerning indoor air quality at the Fingerlakes Library.Surveys filled out by employees stating specific concerns.Articles of interest.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Fire Fighters, Ithaca, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  Correspondence about concern of back injuries and solutions - setting up back clinic. Correspondence on result of a health & safety walk-thru.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - George & Junior Republic, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  Handwritten notes taken about concerns at George & Junior Republic.Correspondence about some reading material and possible training exercises.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Holiday Inn (Box 13, Folder 24)
  "Material Safety Data Sheet", stating hazards of cleaners being used. Memo regarding safety violations.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Human Services Coalition Review Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  Committee's handwritten notes on finances. Grant funding request for 2000.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Ithaca City School District, 1992-2000 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  Press releases about indoor air quality at several Ithaca Schools.Correspondence about indoor air quality. Journal of a custodian bothered, healthwise by indoor air quality.Report from SUNY Health Science Center, Syracuse on Indoor Air Quality for Ithaca City Schools, Boynton & Dewitt. Newspaper clippings.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Ithaca Housing, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  Correspondence and information sheets on workplace hazards.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Ithaca Post Office - APWU Local 1151, 1984-1998 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  Human Resources Accident Logs, Ergonomic Hazards Report for 1998, safety reports stating hazards, and correspondence.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Ithaca School District - History, 1988-1997 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  History Correspondence about indoor air quality at a number of the schools, correspondence about repairing fire damage to Central Elementary.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Ithaca Teachers Assoc. - Training, 1994-1998 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  Information on training opportunities dealing with hazards found in their work area.Pamphlets, information sheets on occupational health & safety issues.IAQ Hazard Speak Out Sheets with comments.Newspaper clippings."An Office Building Occupant's Guide to Indoor Air Quality" by US Environmental Protection Agency, and "Indoor Air Quality (IAQ) in the Modern Office" by the Labor Institute, NYC. "Workplace Violance" by AFSCME, "Asbestos in Schools", by NYCOSH, and "What You Should Know About Indoor Air Quality" by Paraprofessionals and School-Related Personnel, AFT.Right to know/Hazcom, Seminar papers.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Ithaca Transit, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  Correspondence about Diesel Exhaust - Chemical Hazard Training.Copies of the bus driver ergonomics survey.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Lakeside, 1990-2002 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Correspondence about workers picketing. Newspaper clippings.Correspondence about issues of concern and meeting to address them, several copies of "Inside Lakeside: A Newsletter of the Service Employees Int'l Union Local 200A". Copies of Injury/Illness Report and correspondence about training opportunities.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Library SSA, Contract (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Contract Examples Copies of contracts for several libraries in NY State.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - LSDE A - City Schools, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Handwritten notes and correspondence on a Back Clinic given to employees of Ithaca City Schools.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Marathon Schools, 2002-2003 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Handwritten notes about concerns of fumes when Applebee Elementary was being removed.Correspondence and information on mold in the school and the health hazards in poses.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Marietta (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Copy of safety and health hazards paperwork, and training material.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Monarch - UAW 802, 1988-1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Health & safety hazards list, correspondence detailing some of the list and correspondence on training to deal with the hazards.Contract information.Injury/Illness report, Industrial Hygiene Report for Monarch.Copy of health survey.TCLC's suggestions for Health and Safety Contract language.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - NCC Industries, Inc. - UNITE (Box 14, Folder 7)
  Handwritten notes and news clippings about contract negotiations and lay offs at NCC.
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - Negatives (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Picture negatives
- Health & Safety -- Local cases - OCC (Box 14, Folder 9)